http://aymerick.com

I'm a 37 years old software developer living near Rennes, France.

I worked remotely between 2008 and 2014 as a full stack web developer at Fotonauts, a company founded by a group of ex-Apple engineers to create fotopedia, a photo community website.

My current centers of interest are the Go language, the Ember.js framework and home automation, therefore I started a new open source project called Jeego with a web app and DIY devices.

I am also involved in non-profit organizations like 3ailes, Williams Bretagne and Planet Williams, which, as a side effect, gives me the opportunity to acquire experience with Ember.js, Bootstrap and Jekyll... geek forever:)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Fotonauts / Fotopedia (remote)

June 2008 – *September* 2014

I started at Fotonauts by setting up servers with Puppet then Chef. I then developed several features in the rails web app, including photo upload, async job system, users newsfeed, reputation system, achievements system, notifications and newsletter system. Our main database engine was MongoDB and we used Resque to handle async jobs.

Although I have mainly done backend stuff, I also acquired experience in frontend development: CSS, SASS, Javascript, responsive design (even for emails).

The Fotonauts team was based in Paris. Most of the time I worked from home, but one day a week I travelled to Paris to work with my amazing colleagues (and to drink some beers with them).

Apple Contractor at NewLC (Rennes)

December 2004 - May 2008

I met Fotonauts founders while working as a contractor for Apple.

I implemented the SyncML protocol in the iSync synchronisation tool that was shipped with MacOS X. The addition of the SyncML protocol into iSync permitted to add support for tens of new mobile devices for Mac users.

During that mission, I was in direct contact with the development teams of several phone manufacturers like Nokia, Sony-Ericsson and Motorola.

I worked remotely and autonomously from Rennes, reporting to the Apple team located in Paris.

Teleca YacCom (Rennes)

April 2000 – November 2004

I worked four years in the telecom industry, mainly on protocols on the server side (WAP, MMS, EMS, etc.). I also developed on mobile phones (the old ones, not the smart recent ones).

I was a contractor, based in Rennes, for clients like Mitsubishi, Samsung, Alcatel and Philips.

During that period, I started to write my first open-source code as a side project: the WBXML Library, to parse and encode the WBXML format used by several wireless protocols at that time.

EDUCATION

Université de Savoie (1999 – 2000 / Chambery)

DESS Telecom et Reseaux, Computer Systems Networking and Telecommunications.

Université de Rennes I (1997 – 1999 / Rennes)

Licence et Maitrise en Informatique, Computer Science

Université de Rennes I (1995 – 1997 / Rennes)

Deug MIAS, Mathematics and Computer Science

OPEN-SOURCE

Jeego

House monitoring with Jeenode/TinyTX sensors and Go language.

Activr

The activity feeds system that powered fotopedia.

Fwissr

A simple configuration registry tool developed for fotopedia.

WBXML Library

A library to encode and decode WBXML.

ASSOCIATIONS

3ailes

Founder of 3ailes, a local association for parents of children with disabilities.

Williams Bretagne

Member of Williams Bretagne, a local association on Williams Syndrome.

Planet Williams

Creator of Planet Williams, a website that lists the associations related to Williams Syndrome all around the world.

(Formats: PDF - HTML - Markdown)

(Français)